
aardio简介
====================================================
aardio 读音  ['ɑ:diəʊ] 

aardio 专注于桌面软件开发，十余年精益求精，一直保持活跃更新，并且被多年用于生产项目实践，久经测试和锤炼。 
aardio 小、轻、快，轻便利索，体积仅5.6MB，aardio虽然小，但提供了大量开源的标准库、扩展库 - 这些库基本都是由纯aardio代码实现，
涉及到了桌面编程的方方面面。aardio 中的所有库基本都是由作者一个人编写，所以拥有良好的一致性。aardio为每一个库的每一个接口函数都编写了文档，并且提供了大量的演示范例。

aardio 使用流行的类C语法(非常接近Javascript)，在设计中尽可能的避免哗众取宠、标新立异，并且吸取和借鉴流行语言的习惯用法。
不少aardio用户都表示只要有一点编程基础，aardio几乎不用特别学习，看几天就会用了，仅仅是复制拼凑范例都能快速开发出不错的软件。

aardio 是属于易用性极强的动态语言、 但也是一种混合语言，可以罕见的、非常方便的操作静态类型，因此可以直接调用C语言、C++等等静态语言的API接口函数( 不需要像VB那样先声明API )，
aardio可以支持非常多的API调用约定，例如 stdcall，cdecl，thiscall，fastcall，regparm(n) 等调用约定 aardio 都可以支持。因为 aardio奇特的语言特性，aardio的胶水能力极强，
在aardio中可以非常方便的调用C语言、C++、C#、Java、Python、Javascript、Node.Js、Flash ActionScript、PHP、VBScript、NewLISP、Delphi、Go语言 ...... 甚至可以直接嵌入汇编机器码并且转换为普通的aardio函数。
aardio 可直接调用、嵌入、交互的第三方编程语言数量非常多，实现这些第三方语言接口的功能模块基本都是开源的（很多只用了极少的代码）。

aardio 可以嵌入非常多的浏览器控件，例如系统自带的IE控件、WebKit、Electron、CEF3，HTMLayout，Sciter，Chromium ...... 甚至可以直接调用系统安装的Chrome写软件界面。
而且在网页中接用本地接口、以及aardio与浏览器的交互极其方便，例如直接调用Javascript函数，并且在Javascript中直接回调aardio函数，不需要任何复杂的封装和中间件，你甚至可以在Javascript中直接调用WINAPI函数。

aardio不仅可以方便的使用Web技术编写界面，也提供可视化开发工具，可以方便的的通过拖拉传统控件创建程序。
并且aardio提供强大的plus控件（开源）可以方便的实现控件九宫格贴图、透明贴图、可以快速制作出漂亮的界面。而且aardio可以非常方便的生成独立、绿色、无依赖的软件，生成的软件极小，
通常比使用其他开发工具编写的类似功能软件小几倍甚至是几十倍。并且aardio生成的软件可以完美兼容XP,Vista,Win7,Win8,Win10......等所有流行桌面操作系统。

aardio 不仅仅可以开发桌面软件，也可以用于开发网站，aardio可以直接支持与PHP类似的HTML模板语法，提供语言级别的模板解析，
一个aardio源码文件，可以放aardio源码，也可以直接放html，或者放html,aardio混合的模板代码，aardio都能完美支持。并且 aardio可以使用几句代码就可以创建一个微型嵌入式HTTP服务端（可以集成WebSocket服务端），
因此aardio可以非常方便的为浏览器控件提供HTTP服务端，并且像写网站那样写桌面客户端软件。

区别于其他动态语言，aardio可以非常方便的支持真多线程，并且提供大量多线程函数库、演示范例等等。

在aardio中字符串拥有独特的UTF自动标记特性，可以实现自动识别多种不同编码，
虽然aardio默认编码为UTF-8，但字符串中可以存储二进制数据、UTF-8编码文本、UTF-16编码文本等等，
所以aardio不但可以完美支持Unicode，也可以方便的处理二进制数据、或者其他编码的文本。


aardio开发历程:
====================================================

2004年基于开源项目lua开发出LAScript，并随当时的模拟精灵推出，
当时的LAScript仍然是一种纯脚本语言，仅支持动态类型，并不支持静态类型编程，不能直接用于原生开发、不能独立编写应用程序。
只能用于编写脚本（文本格式的解释执行文件）。

于2005年开始基于LAScript研发新的AAuto ，直到2007年底才完成第一个版本，启动了第一个AAU程序。
经过漫长和艰苦的开发，于2010年终于对外发布了第一个公开测试版本.这是一个非常粗糙的版本，工具箱里的控件
大多都是点击提示“尚未完成”，标准库里也只有几个简单的示例，虽然只是发布了一些简单的范例、没有做什么推广工作，
但还是很意外的吸引了不少开发者，直到2011年年底发布1.0正式版，标准库基本完成，已经可以正式的用于开发软件产品。

至2016年正式改名为 aardio，并推出全新基于Unicode内核的aardio10，开始支持网站服务端开发。


关于 Lua
====================================================

Lua is free software distributed under the terms of the MIT license reproduced here. 
Lua may be used for any purpose, including commercial purposes, at absolutely no cost. No paperwork, no royalties, 
no GNU-like "copyleft" restrictions, either. Just download it and use it.

Lua is certified Open Source software.  
Its license is simple and liberal and is compatible with GPL. Lua is not in the public domain and PUC-Rio keeps its copyright.

The spirit of the Lua license is that you are free to use Lua for any purpose at no cost without having to ask us. 
The only requirement is that if you do use Lua, then you should give us credit by including the copyright notice somewhere in your product or its documentation. 
A nice, but optional, way to give us further credit is to include a Lua logo and a link to our site in a web page for your product.

The Lua language is entirely designed, implemented,
 and maintained by a team at PUC-Rio in Brazil. The implementation is not derived from licensed software.

Copyright (C)  1994–2012 Lua.org, PUC-Rio.
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, 
INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. 
IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, 
WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.

LuaCOM is available under the same terms and conditions as the Lua language.

Copyright (C) 1998-2005 Tecgraf, PUC-Rio
Authors: V. Almendra, R. Cerqueira, F. Mascarenhas, and others.

Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy
of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"), to deal
in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights
to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell
copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is
furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in
all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT.  IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM,
OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN
THE SOFTWARE.
